{"Topic": "Art and Culture", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The famous painter Vincent van Gogh belonged to which country?", "op1": "Spain", "op2": "The Netherlands", "op3": "Italy", "op4": "France", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "", "op1": "Bihar", "op2": "Madhya Pradesh", "op3": "West Bengal", "op4": "Rajasthan", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Pablo Picasso belonged to which country?", "op1": "France", "op2": "Germany", "op3": "Spain", "op4": "Italy", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Nand Lal Bose, Manjit Bawa, Tyeb Mehta are", "op1": "Classical Singers", "op2": "English Poets", "op3": "Photographers", "op4": "Painters", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Warli painting is indigenous to which State?", "op1": "Gujarat", "op2": "Rajasthan", "op3": "Odisha", "op4": "Maharashtra", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Raja Harishchandra, an early Indian film was produced by", "op1": "Dada Saheb Phalke", "op2": "Ashok Kumar", "op3": "Ardeshir Irani", "op4": "Gurudatt", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Yavanika or curtain was introduced in Indian theatre by which of the following?", "op1": "Shakas", "op2": "Greeks", "op3": "Huns", "op4": "Persians", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following is a distinguished actor as well as recipient of Jnanpith Award (the highest literary award in India)?", "op1": "Vijay Tendulkar", "op2": "Kaifi Azmi", "op3": "Javed Akhtar", "op4": "Girish Karnad", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Homi Vyarawalla is acclaimed as India's first -", "op1": "Lady Painter", "op2": "Lady Photojournalist", "op3": "Lady Kathak Dancer", "op4": "Lady Playback singer", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Ikebana is Japanese art of :", "op1": "paper craft", "op2": "dress designing", "op3": "miniature tree farming", "op4": "flower arrangement", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who is the voice behind the audio book \"Wings of Fire\" written by former President APJ Abdul Kalam?", "op1": "Om Puri", "op2": "Amitabh Bachchan", "op3": "Girish Karnad", "op4": "Harish Bhimani", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The technique of mural painting executed upon freshly laid lime plaster is known as -", "op1": "Fresco", "op2": "Gouache", "op3": "Tempera", "op4": "Cubism", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Ramkinker Baij was a well known", "op1": "dancer", "op2": "theatre personality", "op3": "violinist", "op4": "sculptor", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which place is famous for embroidered handkerchief?", "op1": "Salem", "op2": "Gadwal", "op3": "Tangaliya", "op4": "Chamba", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Jorasanko Thakur Bari is the ancestral home of which Indian personality?", "op1": "Rabindranath Tagore", "op2": "Pranab Mukherjee", "op3": "Ram Mohan Roy", "op4": "Swami Vivekananda", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The song Ekla Chalo Re (Walk alone) was written by \u2013", "op1": "Subhash Chandra Bose", "op2": "Ishwar Chandra Vidyasagar", "op3": "Rabindra Nath Tagore", "op4": "Aurobindo Ghosh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Indian Council for Cultural Relations was founded by \u2013", "op1": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel", "op2": "", "op3": "Rajagopalachari", "op4": "Maulana Abul Kalam Azad", "op5": "Indira Gandhi", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is/was not a painter?", "op1": "Tyeb Mehta", "op2": "Ramkinkar Baiz", "op3": "Syed Haider Raza", "op4": "Jamini Roy", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "With which form of performing art is Teejan Bai associated?", "op1": "Burra Katha", "op2": "Pandavani", "op3": "Lavani", "op4": "Nautanki", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who amidst the following great music composers was the ruler of a state?", "op1": "Tyagaraja", "op2": "Shyama Shastri", "op3": "Muthuswami Dikshitar", "op4": "Swathi Tirunal Rama Varma"}, {"Question": "Who wrote the lyrics of the song Aye Mere Watan Ke Logo?", "op1": "Manoj Kumar", "op2": "Pradeep", "op3": "Shailendra", "op4": "Raghupati Sahay \u2018Firaq\u2019", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Raghu Rai is a well-known \u2013", "op1": "Painter", "op2": "Film Director", "op3": "Photographer", "op4": "Sportsperson", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The National Anthem of Bangladesh was written by \u2013", "op1": "Mujib-ur-rahman", "op2": "Mohd Iqbal", "op3": "Rabindranath Tagore", "op4": "Bhupen Hazarika", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Match List I with List II and select the correct answer using the code given below the lists.", "op1": "A - 2; B - 1; C - 3; D - 4", "op2": "A - 4; B - 3; C - 1; D - 2", "op3": "A - 2; B - 4; C - 1; D - 3", "op4": "A - 4; B - 1; C - 3; D - 2", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "de:", "op1": "Vincent van Gogh", "op2": "Rembrandt", "op3": "Raphael", "op4": "Pablo Picasso", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following painted the famous painting Guernica?", "op1": "Painter", "op2": "Musician", "op3": "Singer", "op4": "Physician", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Raja Ravi Varma was a famous \u2013", "op1": "Haiku", "op2": "Ikebana", "op3": "Origami", "op4": "Karaoke", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Japanese art of paper folding is known as \u2013", "op1": "Pune", "op2": "New Delhi", "op3": "Mumbai", "op4": "Ahmedabad", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which city is the Film and Television Institute of India located?", "op1": "Bhagwan Das", "op2": "MM Malviya", "op3": "Rabindranath Tagore", "op4": "Mahatma Gandhi", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who founded the Kashi Vidyapeeth in Varanasi in 1921?", "op1": "Ludhiana", "op2": "Chamba", "op3": "Barmer", "op4": "Lucknow", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The city famous for its Chikankari  work of embroidery is -", "op1": "Tamil Nadu", "op2": "Jharkhand", "op3": "Nagaland", "op4": "Mizoram", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Irula tribe, well-known for snake-catching are native to \u2013", "op1": "Tamil Nadu", "op2": "Telangana", "op3": "Karnataka", "op4": "Andhra Pradesh", "Answer": 4}]}